Hello everyone, welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're bringing you the second part of Christmas Chronicles.
今天我们要为大家带来圣诞编年史的第二部分。
Another Christmas lesson to get you in the Christmas spirit.
另一节圣诞课程，让你感受圣诞气氛。
Christmas and useful language for all of our listeners today.
今天为所有听众带来圣诞和实用语言。
That's right.
没错。
In today's lesson, we'll be learning some great Christmas vocabulary.
在今天的课程中，我们将学习一些很棒的圣诞词汇。
And police-related vocabulary as well.
还有与警察相关的词汇。
Now, Christmas, police vocabulary, how exactly does that fit together?
那么，圣诞和警察词汇，它们怎么凑到一起的呢？
Well, they don't.
嗯，它们不搭。
But here at EnglishPod, we can make anything happen.
但在EnglishPod，我们可以让任何事情发生。
So that's why we have done this.
所以我们才这么做了。
To be creative.
为了有创意。
So, let's take a look at our vocabulary preview for this lesson.
那么，让我们来看看这节课的词汇预览。
Vocabulary Preview.
词汇预览。
In today's vocabulary preview, we've got two words from our dialogue that you will need
在今天的词汇预览中，我们有两个来自对话的单词，你需要
to know to understand this dialogue.
知道它们才能理解这段对话。
The first one is elves.
第一个是elves。
Elves.
Elves。
And this is the plural of the word elf.
这是单词elf的复数形式。
Elf, right.
Elf，对。
So elves are?
那么elves是？
Little people.
小矮人。
Little people with pointy hats?
戴着尖帽的小矮人？
With pointy hats.
戴着尖帽。
Sense is helpers.
感觉像是帮手。
Okay.
好的。
So elves.
所以是elves。
Elves.
Elves。
Our next word is candy cane.
下一个词是candy cane。
Candy cane.
Candy cane。
So a candy cane is a traditional Christmas candy, right?
那么candy cane是一种传统的圣诞糖果，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
It's red and white.
它是红白相间的。
And it kind of shaped like a J?
它形状有点像J吗？
Like a J, yeah.
像J，是的。
Okay.
好的。
It's very traditional.
它非常传统。
Yeah, you hang them on the tree and you eat them at Christmas time.
是的，你把他们挂在树上，然后在圣诞节的时候吃。
Yes.
是的。
Tastes like peppermint.
尝起来像薄荷。
Okay, well, I guess we're ready to listen to our dialogue for the first time.
好了，我想我们准备好第一次听对话了。
And it's going to be kind of fast, but...
语速会有点快，但是……
Don't worry if you don't understand everything because we'll come back and talk about some
如果没全听懂也别担心，因为我们之后会回来讨论一些
of the language later.
语言点。
Santa Claus is coming straight to the dinner table.
圣诞老人直接来到餐桌旁。
Really, fellas?
真的吗，伙计们？
You can't take me to jail.
你们不能把我关进监狱。
Don't you know who I am?
你们不知道我是谁吗？
Kris Kringle, you know?
克里斯·克林格尔，知道吗？
Papa Noel, Père Noel, Baba Natale.
圣诞老人，圣诞老人，圣诞老人，圣诞老人。
Shungudan no Chant.
圣诞老人。
Yeah, yeah, we've heard that one before, haven't we, Joe?
是啊是啊，我们以前听过这个，对吧，乔？
Yeah, last week we booked this guy who claimed to be a tooth fairy.
是啊，上周我们抓了个自称是牙仙的家伙。
Can you believe that?
你能相信吗？
It's Christmas Eve and I have all these presents to deliver.
今天是平安夜，我还有这么多礼物要送。
Where's your Christmas spirit?
你们的圣诞精神去哪儿了？
What will happen when all the children wake up tomorrow and don't find any gifts in their
明天早上孩子们醒来，发现袜子里
stockings?
没有礼物，那该怎么办？
Sorry, buddy, you're parked in a no-parking zone.
抱歉，老兄，你停在禁停区了。
You were speeding and you have no ID.
你超速了，而且没有身份证。
Besides that, even if we let you go now, your sleigh's been impounded and those reindeer
除此之外，就算我们现在放你走，你的雪橇也被扣押了，那些驯鹿
were taken to the city zoo.
被送到了城市动物园。
What?
什么？
This is unbelievable.
这简直难以置信。
What's this world coming to?
这个世界到底怎么了？
Christmas is ruined.
圣诞节毁了。
What's that up ahead?
前面那是什么？
It looks like...
看起来像……
Elves!
小精灵！
Whoa, they're shooting candy canes!
哇，他们在发射拐杖糖！
Mayday, mayday!
求救，求救！
We're under heavy attack!
我们正遭受猛烈攻击！
We need backup!
我们需要支援！
Okay, so Santa has escaped from the police car.
好了，圣诞老人从警车里逃出来了。
Hooray!
万岁！
Thank God!
谢天谢地！
It's like a war over there.
那边简直像打仗一样。
They were really firing everything.
他们真的火力全开。
I know, I mean, those elves are...
我知道，我是说，那些精灵真是……
Aggressive.
有攻击性。
Very aggressive.
非常有攻击性。
Okay, well, we can take a look at some great vocabulary from this dialogue.
好了，我们可以看看这段对话里的一些好词汇。
Why don't we start with our language takeaway for today?
我们先从今天的语言要点开始吧？
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
In today's language takeaway, we have five really important words that we hope you will
今天的语言要点中，我们有五个非常重要的单词，希望你们能
take away from the lesson.
从这节课中学到。
Exactly, and the first word that we have today is booked.
没错，今天的第一个词是 booked。
Booked.
Booked。
Booked is another way of saying...
Booked 是另一种说法……
Arrested.
被逮捕。
Yeah, it's a slang word, hey?
是的，这是个俚语，对吧？
It's kind of slang, yeah.
算是俚语，没错。
Yeah.
嗯。
It's a slang word, booked.
这是个俚语，booked。
Okay, next word, speeding.
好的，下一个词，超速。
Speeding.
超速。
So, Santa was speeding because he was...
所以，圣诞老人超速是因为他……
Going too fast.
开得太快了。
Driving too fast, yeah.
开车太快了，嗯。
Okay.
好的。
Going over the speed limit.
超过了限速。
Exactly.
没错。
Third word today is...
今天的第三个词是……
Impounded.
被扣押。
被扣押了。
That's when your car gets arrested.
就是你的车被逮捕了。
Your car gets arrested.
你的车被逮捕了。
Yeah, they take your car to car jail.
是啊，他们把车带到车监狱去了。
Okay, so my car is in car jail.
好吧，所以我的车在车监狱里。
I think I understand.
我想我明白了。
It's impounded.
被扣押了。
Okay, so the police take my car and I have to...
好吧，所以警察把我的车拖走了，我得……
Pay to get it out.
花钱把它赎回来。
Okay.
好的。
Let's move to our next word, ruined.
我们来看下一个词，ruined。
Ruined.
Ruined。
We have a few examples for us to listen to, to understand the meaning of this word.
我们有几个例子可以听，来理解这个词的意思。
Example one.
例子一。
It's been raining for five days.
已经下了五天雨了。
Our vacation is ruined.
我们的假期全毁了。
Example two.
例子二。
Look at this hole.
看这个洞。
You've ruined my favorite pair of jeans.
你把我最喜欢的牛仔裤弄坏了。
Example three.
例子三。
Sam, you've been caught stealing from the company.
山姆，你偷公司东西被抓到了。
Your chances for a promotion are ruined.
你升职的机会泡汤了。
Okay, great examples and basically ruined means...
好的，很好的例子，基本上 ruined 的意思是……
Destroyed.
被毁掉了。
Yeah, messed up.
对，搞砸了。
Messed up.
搞砸了。
Okay.
好的。
So, our next word, backup.
那么，下一个词，backup。
Backup.
Backup。
So, now for our last word.
现在是我们最后一个词。
Okay, so now for our last word and language takeaway, backup.
好的，现在是我们最后一个词和语言要点，backup。
Backup.
Backup。
So, backup is...
所以 backup 的意思是……
Help.
帮助。
Yeah.
是啊。
Right?
对吧？
So, when you call for backup, you call for help.
所以，当你呼叫支援时，就是请求帮助。
Yeah, you see it all the time in war movies, police, call for backup.
是啊，你在战争片、警匪片里经常看到，呼叫支援。
Yeah.
嗯。
Right?
对吧？
So, important to point out that here, the pronunciation and stress of this phrase is
所以，需要指出的是，这个短语的发音和重音
really important, hey?
非常重要，对吧？
Yes, yes.
是的，是的。
You have to say backup.
你必须说 backup。
Backup.
Backup。
Yeah.
嗯。
So, both words are stressed at about the same level, hey?
所以，两个词的重音差不多一样重，对吧？
Backup.
Backup。
Because if you were to say back up...
因为如果你说 back up...
That means to move back.
那意思是往后退。
Exactly.
没错。
Yeah, it's different.
对，不一样。
So, backup, backup.
所以，backup, backup。
Yes, the stress is important.
是的，重音很重要。
The stress.
重音。
All right.
好了。
Well, you know what?
嗯，你知道吗？
With those words in mind, it's time for us to listen to the dialogue a second time.
记住了这些词，我们该听第二遍对话了。
Really, fellas, you can't take me to jail.
说真的，伙计们，你们不能把我关进监狱。
Don't you know who I am?
你们不知道我是谁吗？
Kris Kringle, you know?
克里斯·克林格尔，知道吗？
Papa Noel, Parent Noel, Baba Natale, Shonda Lawrent.
圣诞老人，圣诞老人，圣诞老人，圣诞老人。
Yeah, yeah, we've heard that one before.
是啊，是啊，我们以前听过这个说法。
Haven't we, Joe?
对吧，乔？
Yeah, last week we booked this guy who claimed to be the tooth fairy.
是啊，上周我们抓了个自称是牙仙的家伙。
Can you believe that?
你能相信吗？
It's Christmas Eve, and I have all these presents to deliver.
今天是平安夜，我还有这么多礼物要送。
Where's your Christmas spirit?
你们的圣诞精神去哪儿了？
What will happen when all the children wake up tomorrow and don't find any gifts in their
明天早上孩子们醒来，发现袜子里
stockings?
没有礼物，怎么办？
Sorry, buddy, you were parked in a no-parking zone.
抱歉，老兄，你把车停在禁停区了。
You were speeding, and you have no ID.
你超速了，而且没有身份证。
Besides that, even if we let you go now, your sleigh has been impounded, and those reindeer
除此之外，就算我们现在放你走，你的雪橇也被扣押了，那些驯鹿也...
were taken to the city zoo.
被带到了城市动物园。
What?
什么？
This is unbelievable.
这太难以置信了。
What's the world coming to?
这世界到底怎么了？
Christmas is ruined.
圣诞节毁了。
What's that up ahead?
前面那是什么？
It looks like elves.
看起来像精灵。
Whoa, they're shooting candy canes.
哇，他们在射拐杖糖。
Mayday, mayday.
求救，求救。
We are under heavy attack.
我们正遭受猛烈攻击。
We need backup.
我们需要支援。
Okay, so without the sound effects and without any noise, I think it's much more clear now,
好了，没有音效和噪音，我觉得现在清楚多了，
right?
对吧？
A little less dramatic.
没那么戏剧化了。
Less dramatic, but good language.
没那么戏剧化，但语言很好。
Yes.
是的。
Speaking of good language, there's some great phrases I want to look at in this dialogue,
说到好语言，这段对话里有一些很棒的短语我想看看，
and so let's do that in Putting It Together.
我们就在“整合”环节来做这件事。
Putting It Together.
整合。
We have two phrases in Putting It Together that we want to show you how you can use in
在“整合”环节中，我们有两个短语想展示给你们，它们可以在很多不同情境中使用。
many different situations.
在对话中，我们听到了这个。
In the dialogue, we heard this.
上周我们预约了一个自称是牙仙的家伙。
Last week we booked this guy who claimed to be a tooth fairy.
所以当你声称自己是某物时，你在说你是某物，但可能不是真的，对吧？
So when you claim to be something, you're saying that you are something, but it might
对。
not be true, right?
例如，你可以说，这个女人自称是你妻子。
Right.
但她不是。
So for example, you can say, this woman claimed to be your wife.
But she's not.
我们还有几个其他例子，展示如何使用“声称”这个短语。
例子一。
We have a few other examples of how you can use the phrase claim to.
丹尼尔自称是政府部长的儿子，但后来我们发现他在撒谎。
Example one.
例子二。
Daniel claimed to be the son of a government minister, but later we found out that he was
罪犯声称有枪。
lying.
例子三。
Example two.
这里的这个男人声称认识你父亲。
The criminals claim to have a gun.
这个短语真棒。
Example three.
只需把它和另一个动词搭配，意思就不同了，但仍然表达
This man here is claiming to know your father.
这个短语真棒。
That's such a great phrase.
只需把它和另一个动词搭配，意思就不同了，但仍然表达
Just by putting it together with another verb means something different, but still expresses
这个短语真棒。
that same idea.
同样的想法。
Right.
对。
Claim to have.
声称有。
She claimed to have a baby or something.
她声称自己有个孩子什么的。
Yeah.
嗯。
Okay.
好的。
So let's move to our next phrase.
那我们来看下一个短语。
Under heavy.
遭受严重的。
So in the dialogue, they said we're under heavy attack.
在对话中，他们说我们遭受了猛烈的攻击。
Right.
对。
You can also use this phrase in a couple of other ways.
这个短语还有其他几种用法。
Example one.
例子一。
We're under heavy attack.
我们遭受了猛烈的攻击。
Example two.
例子二。
We're under heavy fire.
我们遭到了猛烈的炮火。
Example three.
例子三。
The prime minister is under heavy security.
首相处于严密的安保之下。
So if you're under heavy fire.
所以如果你遭到猛烈炮火。
Means that there's a lot of fire.
意思是火力很猛。
Like gunfire.
比如枪火。
Gunfire, yeah.
枪火，对。
Yeah, not like fire fire.
对，不是那种火焰。
Yeah.
嗯。
Okay.
好的。
And if you're under heavy security.
而如果你处于严密安保之下。
It means that you have a lot of security, a lot of bodyguards or a lot of.
意思是安保很严密，有很多保镖或者很多。
Right.
对。
Like a prime minister or president would be under heavy security.
比如首相或总统会处于严密安保之下。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay.
好的。
A couple of great phrases.
几个很棒的短语。
Really good phrases and with this, we can listen to our dialogue a third time.
非常好的短语，这样我们就可以第三次听对话了。
Really, Fuzz, you can't take me to jail.
真的吗，Fuzz，你不能把我关进监狱。
Don't you know who I am?
你不知道我是谁吗？
Kris Kringle, you know.
Kris Kringle，你知道的。
Papa Noel, Père Noel, Baba Natale.
Papa Noel, Père Noel, Baba Natale。
Chantant l'Enfant.
Chantant l'Enfant。
Yeah, yeah.
是啊，是啊。
We've heard that one before, haven't we, Joe?
我们以前就听过这种话了，对吧，乔？
Yeah.
是啊。
I even book this guy who claimed to be a tooth fairy.
我甚至预约了一个自称是牙仙的家伙。
Can you believe that?
你能相信吗？
It's Christmas Eve and I have all these presents to deliver.
今天是平安夜，我还有这么多礼物要送。
Where's your Christmas spirit?
你的圣诞精神去哪儿了？
What will happen when all the children wake up tomorrow and don't find any gifts in their
明天早上孩子们醒来，发现袜子里
stockings?
没有礼物，那该怎么办？
Sorry, buddy, you're parked in a no parking zone.
抱歉，伙计，你停在了禁停区。
You were speeding and you have no ID.
你超速了，而且没有身份证。
Besides that, even if we let you go now, your sleigh's been impounded and those reindeer
除此之外，就算我们现在放你走，你的雪橇也被扣押了，那些驯鹿
were taken to the city zoo.
被送到了城市动物园。
What?
什么？
This is unbelievable.
这简直难以置信。
What's this world coming to?
这个世界到底怎么了？
Christmas is ruined.
圣诞节被毁了。
What's that up ahead?
前面那是什么？
It looks like elves.
看起来像小精灵。
Whoa, they're shooting candy canes.
哇，他们在射拐杖糖。
Mayday, mayday, we're under heavy attack.
求救，求救，我们正遭受猛烈攻击。
We need backup.
我们需要支援。
So, Marco, the police mentioned something about the tooth fairy.
那么，马可，警察提到了牙仙的事。
The tooth fairy.
牙仙。
I don't know, maybe some of our listeners don't know this story about the tooth fairy.
我不知道，也许有些听众不知道牙仙的故事。
So can I go ahead and say it?
那我可以直接讲吗？
Yes, go ahead.
好，请讲。
Okay, well, when you're small and you lose a tooth.
好吧，当你小时候掉了一颗牙。
Your baby teeth.
你的乳牙。
Yeah, you put it underneath your pillow and then you go to sleep.
对，你把它放在枕头下面，然后去睡觉。
And then in the night, the tooth fairy comes into the house, flies into the house, sneaks
然后晚上，牙仙会进屋，飞进屋里，偷偷
under your pillow, takes the tooth and puts money there.
钻到你的枕头下，拿走牙齿，放上钱。
I see.
我明白了。
So this is a story that parents tell their kids about what happens to their baby teeth.
所以这是父母告诉孩子关于乳牙去向的故事。
And they get money in exchange for it.
而且他们用牙齿换钱。
Right.
对。
So I guess it takes away the sadness of losing that tooth.
我想这能减轻掉牙的伤感。
Yeah.
是啊。
But in South America, for example, we have the tooth mouse.
但在南美，比如我们那里，有牙鼠。
The tooth mouse.
牙鼠。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
What is it?
是什么？
How does it call them in Spanish?
在西班牙语里它叫什么？
Oh, well, in some places it's called Ratoncito Perez.
哦，嗯，有些地方叫它 Ratoncito Perez。
Like it has a last name Perez.
就像它有个姓 Perez 一样。
Oh, really?
哦，真的吗？
In other places, it's just called Ratoncito, which means mouse.
在其他地方，它就叫 Ratoncito，意思是老鼠。
Okay, so it'd be like tooth fairy Smith.
好的，那就好比牙仙史密斯。
Yeah, tooth fairy Smith.
对，牙仙史密斯。
And it's the same thing.
而且是一回事。
It's a little mouse that comes in and steals a little tooth from you and leaves money in
它是一只小老鼠，进来偷走你的牙齿，然后留下钱作为
exchange.
交换。
Cool.
酷。
Very cool.
非常酷。
Yeah.
是啊。
So we go from Santa Claus to Guns and Wars to the tooth fairy.
所以我们从圣诞老人聊到了枪炮与战争，又聊到了牙仙。
Only at EnglishPod.
只有在 EnglishPod。
Exactly.
没错。
All right, guys.
好了，各位。
I hope you enjoyed today's lesson.
希望你们喜欢今天的课程。
If you have any questions or comments about the lesson, please visit our website, EnglishPod.com.
如果对课程有任何问题或评论，请访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
All right.
好的。
Well, we're out of time.
嗯，我们时间到了。
We got to go.
我们得走了。
We've got some Christmas shopping to do.
我们还有些圣诞购物要做。
Yes, Christmas shopping.
是的，圣诞购物。
So we'll see you guys later.
那我们回头见。
And until then, it's goodbye.
在那之前，再见。
Goodbye.
再见。